CAMILLE HANSEN-THEOBALD

New York City, NY

Phone: 916-276-6240 | Email: camilleht@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/camille-hansen-theobald

GitHub: https://github.com/camilleNicoleT/Portfolio.git

SUMMARY

Full Stack web developer leveraging education and performing arts background to build engaging user experiences. Recently earned a certificate in full stack development from Columbia University, with newly developed skills in JavaScript, Node.js, React and responsive web design. Known as an inventive problem solver excited to develop intuitive apps, with a focus on mobile-first design and development. With each project, striving to attract the audience with a pleasant user experience. Excited to use these skills as a valuable team-member, at a company with similar values, to build better experiences on the web.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Libraries: React, jQuery, BootStrap

Databases: MongoDB, SQL/sequelize

Query languages: GraphQL
Environment: NODE.js
Frameworks: Express.js,

Apps: PWA

PROJECTS

STICKER BOOK https://sticker-book.git Summary: Goal tracking web application with ability to encourage other user's goals.

Role: Front-End pages and components

Tools: MongoDB, GraphQL, React, Tailwind, Express, Node.js, Yarn

INDUBITABLY https://github.com/geo-a-mac/indubidubly.git

Summary: Job seeking app based off of skills

Role: Front-End

Tools: Node.js, Express.js, Handlebars.js, MySQL/Sequelize

MAKI MAKU https://camillenicolet.github.io/MakiMaku/ | https://github.com/camilleNicoleT/MakiMaku.git

Summary: Stay at home date ideas generator

Role: CSS and API logic

Tools: Javascript, CSS, Materialize, Third Party API's

EXPERIENCE

American Musical and Dramatic Academy | New York City, NY Assistant to Student Affairs and Housing | May 2009 - PRESENT

- Help improve communication tracking with students by using StarRez and CampusView web applications.
- Successfully coordinated transported 500 student's belongings when Covid-19 closed down the city
- Improved Student R.A. performance by 15% updating training protocol and guiding them throughout the semester
- Raise student engagement at Residential events by documenting interested and cultivating a community with consistent communication
- Upgrade passive programming to increase education outside the classroom

United Stations Radio Network & Storic Media | New York City, NY Writer | December 2016 - PRESENT

- Developed new comedic scripts each week based on current news topics to engage the listeners
- Polished and wrote Season 2 and 3 of an established children's Story Podcast "Detective Dexter" and gained 10% more listeners

Cieri Media I New York City, NY

Producer and Host | December 2014 - August 2016

- Helped build quality video content for the NY Indie Film festival and the Cieri Media Youtube page
- Presented engaging awards ceremonies annually for 4 years.

EDUCATION

Web Development Certificate: Columbia University | NYC, NY

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, GraphQL, the MERN stack and ReactJS.

Certification: AMDA, NYC, NY Musical Theater Performance conservatory.